

jacob.kim.johnson@gmail.com

wordstosong.me

in/jacobkimjohnson

PHONE

(608)790-7675

LOCATION

Los Angeles, CA

I'm a design, programming, and marketing professional with a passion for all things creative. Having a strong desire for problem-solving, my creativity, thoughtfulness, critical thinking, and collaborative nature have been beneficial as strengths, both personally and professionally. I have worked for organizations that include nonprofits and start-ups, which have given me the distinct ability to examine situations and consider strategies from different perspectives. It has helped me be more open-minded as I figure out

JACOB KIM JOHNSON

EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer and Web Developer

Self-employed Aug. 2017 - Present

- Challenged visual web layout skills by designing and developing user-centric, mobile-first web apps from scratch (using HTML, CSS, and Javascript)
- Created wireframes and mockups of web app designs

the details, while focusing on the big picture.

- Refined typography execution with font pairings, hierarchy, and spacing
- Refined other aspects of visual design, like color theory and visual hierarchy/ spacing
- Designed and created graphics for logos and web content
- Researched ongoing design trends, both in UX/UI and visual composition

Graphic Designer, Web Content Coordinator, and UX/UI Designer

CBE International Jul. 2014 - Sep. 2017

- Helped plan, research, test, and implement website functionality and design to improve user experience for conversion-oriented interface
- Created wireframes and mockups of web pages for updates and redesigns
- Created UX user personas and conceptualized journey maps
- Designed logo concepts for the organization's main brand and blog
- Created graphic images for internal (e.g. web headers) and external (e.g. advertisements) purposes
- Designed and edited printed marketing materials and book covers/layouts
- Coordinated with all departments and developers to ensure brand and visual consistency
- Edited and managed web content with Drupal CMS and HTML/CSS
- Improved social media strategies to be more visual, better suit reader interest, and increase interaction

Marketing Specialist (Contractor)

CATS Software, Inc. Apr. 2014 - Jul. 2014

- Experienced Agile methodology with daily meetings and JIRA for project management
- Created icons, graphics, and cartoons as companions to blog articles and social media posts
- Managed social media accounts and helped facilitate conversation for start-up organization
- Wrote industry relevant blog articles to help push organizational narrative voice

Marketing Intern

High Noon Saloon Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2011

- Edited website design to improve clarity of information
- Created graphics for upcoming events to manage and share via social media
- Wrote and edited content for the website, regarding upcoming events

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts

Luther College **Graduated May 2010**

- Major: Business Management
- Minor: Psychology
- **Emphasis: Marketing**

Certificate

Minneapolis Community and Technical College Completed Dec. 2014

- Graphic Design
- Web Design

SKILLED WITH

Photoshop Illustrator InDesign

> Acrobat Sketch

Invision